COLE POPPSINGER

Edmonds, WA colepopp@gmail.com 206.913.8833

A data scientist with twenty years of customer-facing leadership experience.

Trained in high-intensity environments, focused on reducing barriers and creating sustainable solutions while building dynamic teams. Organization, analysis, and continuous improvement are my happy-place

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cole-po ppsinger/ https://github.com/colepoppsinger https://colepoppsinger.github.io/

EXPERIENCE

Starbucks Coffee Co, WA, OR, MA — *Multiple Roles (barista to multi-unit manager and trainer)*Apr 2002 - Nov 2021

Store Manager Trainer 2008-2018

Hosted immersion trainings for corporate partners from coordinator to executive Trained 10 store managers

Multi-unit Manager 2012-2014

Managed 2-12 stores over period of 2 years

Supported development in-role of store manager peers

Regular stand-in for District Manager during vacation coverage and operations meetings

Test Store Manager 2013-2016

Managed store as testing environment for new products, processes, and technologies Daily communication with project stakeholders to implement changes and track progress

Coffee Master 2005-2021

Completed advanced training in coffee education, acted as 'coffee ambassador' at coffee expos

Barista, Shift Supervisor, Assistant Manager 2002-2008

Managed daily store operations: cash handling, coaching and development of employees, safety and security measures, inventory management, customer service

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Remote — Certificate in Data Science

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

Twelve-week immersive Data Science course

Out In Front Leadership Program, Seattle, WA - Certificate of Completion

Sept 2019 - May 2020

Nine-month professional development program for LGBTQIA-identified leaders

 $\textbf{University of Massachusetts,} \ \textbf{Amherst,} \ \textbf{MA} - \textit{BA, French Language and Cultural Studies}$

2017-2018 Degree Completion: Leadership Studies

1998-2002 French Language and Cultural Studies, Film

University of Paris VII, Paris, France - Study Abroad (Film, History, Sociology)

Aug 2000 - July 2001

VOLUNTEER

Mainstay, Seattle, WA 2013-2017

Collaborated with employees with disabilities and their support staff to ensure a successful work environment through work routines (Weekly)

Volunteered at annual fund-raising events and recruited additional volunteers

Boys & Girls Club Youthforce, Seattle, WA 2013-2017

Held bi-quarterly events supporting at-risk youth seeking practice preparing for real-life job interviews

Farestart, Seattle, WA 2008-2014

Matched store managers with graduates of "barista bootcamp" for practice interviews (Monthly)

Center for Wooden Boats, Seattle, WA 2008-2013

Staffed model boat pond with volunteers who collected donations for the organization, and instructed public in basic sailing techniques (Weekly May-Sept)

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Data Visualization

Data Wrangling

Programming

Statistics

Problem-solving

Group Facilitation

Project Management

Talent Development

Merchandising

Cross-functional Relationships

P+L mgmt/business planning

PLATFORMS

Adobe Suite

Microsoft Office Suite

Taleo, Kronos, POS

Tableau

Streamlit

LANGUAGES

Python

Html

SQL

Javascript

English

French

AWARDS

'Peer of the Year' 2017

'Store Manager of the Quarter' Q2

2015